# **NIRAJ DILIP CHAVAN**

# Web/UI Developer

#### LINKEDIN:

https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

#### **PORTFOLIO:**

https://devnirajc.github.io/niraj-chavan/

#### **PROFILE**

UI Developer with 8+ years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex ecommerce sites. An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards. Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

#### **CONTACT**

PHONE: +91 96071 95436 / +91 87932 39176

EMAIL: nirajd327@gmail.com

**ADDRESS:** 7<sup>th</sup> Heaven, B-404, B Wing, Sr. No. 6, Hissa No. 3, D. N. Parande Park, Dhanori, Pune – 411015,

Maharashtra, India

#### **KEY SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4/5, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Angular, ReactJS, Node JS, GraphQL, JSON, SVN, GIT, MongoDB, Jira, Rally, Microsoft Azure, Webpack, NPM, Karma, Jest, Chart JS

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

DATE OF BIRTH: 07/08/1992
MARITAL STATUS: Married
NATIONALITY: Indian

LANGUAGES KNOWN: English, Hindi, Marathi

### **EDUCATION**

# BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)

Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University

August 2011 – July 2014 Grade (%): 63.89

### **DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING**

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education)

July 2008 – July 2011 Grade (%): 83.03

#### SECONDRY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board June 2007 – July 2008 Grade (%): 86.46

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# JP MORGAN CHASE & CO., PUNE, INDIA

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

15/12/2021 - Present

Develop modern web applications and services in agile sprints. Write clean, efficient, reliable code using proven, reliable components and design patterns. Implement and write unit tests. Follow established best practices and processes to ensure code quality with an eye for performance and maintainability.

### SCHLUMBERGER, PUNE, INDIA

#### **UI Developer**

23/09/2019 - 09/12/2021

Help to integrate Wijmo in angular component with engineering team. Build reusable libraries and code for future use. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability. Reviewing requirements and design to build new UI features.

# XPANXION INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD. (BLUECONCH TECHNOLOGIES), PUNE, INDIA

#### **Senior UI Engineer**

31/01/2017 - 20/09/2019

Implementation of angular custom reusable components, JWT token implementation, performance optimization and API integration.

# CONNECT 91 WEB SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD. (POLYSCRIPTS INFOTECH PVT. LTD.), PUNE, INDIA

# **Frontend Developer**

14/12/2015 - 30/01/2017

UI enhancement designs for better user experience, convert PSD into HTML and make the websites compatible with all browsers.

# WHITECODE IT SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD., PUNE, INDIA Software Developer

03/07/2014 - 11/12/2015

Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

#### **PROJECTS**

# PROJECT NAME - FIELD LOGISTIC MODULE Role and Responsibility -

- Implement major features with limited guidance from leads and managers
- Demonstrate a passion for web development, have an eye for well-designed user interfaces, and be extremely detail-oriented.
- Be a technical expert, mentor junior developers and share your expertise with other software engineers to strengthen our team
- In addition to new projects, be willing to add new features and refactor parts of established projects
- Provide accurate timing estimates on work. Collaborate with User Experience Designers, User Researchers and Product Managers to ensure our solutions meet users' needs with maximum usability.
- Collaborate with Software Managers and Business analysts to develop realistic implementation plans with a focus on quality, sustainability and delivering value to our clients.
- Contribute to documentation (e.g.: instructional and technical specifications).

Team Size - 15

Role - Sr. Software Engineer

Skills - Angular 12, HTML, SCSS, Chart JS, MS Azure, JavaScript, ECMAScript, Typescript, Git, Abstract, Jira, Dynatrace, SonarQube

#### PROJECT NAME - ECOM SHOPPING APPLICATION

#### Role and Responsibility -

- An online website for e-Commerce shopping build on React JS, Express JS, Node JS and mongo DB.
- To create website layout/user interfaces by using HTML/CSS technologies with responsive and flexible UI.
- Build back-end flow and architecture. Writing code using best practices. Build admin panel for multiple roles with sets of permissions.
- Build architectural design of product. Design, develop and deploy modules of product. Apply deep understanding of JavaScript and React JS to build reusable UI components in a multi-device, modern web UI framework.

Team Size - 2

Role - UI Developer

Skills - React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, Git, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Heroku

#### **PROJECT NAME - K7 SECURITY**

#### Role and Responsibility -

- To build dashboard for end customers to manage multiple devices from online website account.
- Develop software solutions using industry best practices and in the area of security and performance in a web and architecture environment.
- Collaborates with team and business owners in the design and analysis phases as part of self-organizing feature teams.
- Maintain source-code repository, participate in Code Reviews, and conduct design reviews. Participate in deployment of code into production.

Team Size - 8

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap, JHipster, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Rally

#### **PROJECT NAME - SCOPERETAIL**

#### Role and Responsibility -

- Design and developed UI Interface with optimized solution for E-commerce retail product.
- To create custom angular 5 components for Internal framework.
- To create UI mock-ups, wire frames and responsive design using HTML 5, Bootstrap 4 and JavaScript.
- Provide best solutions for performance optimization techniques and unit testing strategy.
- Build deployment strategy and micro web-based service architecture.
- Integrated web rest API with front end application. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.

# Team Size - 22

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Jira, Jasmine, Karma

#### **PROJECT NAME - CERTASLIM**

#### Role and Responsibility -

- Design and develop high performance web applications using Front-end technologies.
- Use mark-up languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages. Develop new user-facing features.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use. Create quality mockups and prototypes.
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability.
- Work closely with juniors and provide strong code reviews and feedback.
- Continually evaluate emerging frameworks and technologies to identify opportunities, trends and best practices that strengthen the development team.

Team Size - 6

Role - UI Developer

Skills - Angular, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 3, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Zoho